# Aline Schneider

Boca Raton, FL 33486

aline.schv@gmail.com 561-283-9445

linkedin.com/in/aline-schneider github.com/alineschneider

# **Summary**

Data Analyst with a passion for drawing insights from data to inform decision-making. With leadership experience, excels at both working independently and in collaboration to solve challenging problems. Strong data analysis professional with a certification on Data Analytics and Visualization from UC, Berkeley.

### **Skills**

Data Analysis
Python / Pandas / Numpy
HTML / CSS / JavaScript
R
Machine Learning
PostgreSQL
Tableau / Plotly visualizations
Flask / APIs / Web Scraping
Microsoft Office

### **Education**

## Data Analytics and Visualization University of California Berkeley

March 2020 - August 2020

# **Bachelor's in Civil Engineering** Federal University of Espírito Santo -Vitória, Brazil

February 2005 - August 2010

#### Certification



# **Work Experience**

#### **Senior Optimization Analyst**

HiConversion – Boca Raton - FL February 2019 - present

Lead the Optimization Analyst team, create A/B and multivariate testing strategies for e-commerce websites to improve user experience and increase revenue; analyze the data; interpret results; create reports and present them to clients. Assist Sales department with presentations to prospective clients.

#### **Budget and Finance Analyst**

Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil June 2014 - December 2017 (3 years 7 months)

IBGE is a Brazilian Federal Government institution; the role involved extracting, treating and analyzing data reports relative to financial expenses; registering and controlling warranties and security deposits by third party companies providing services to IBGE.

#### **Administrative Analyst**

Vale S.A. - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil August 2011 - September 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Vale is a Brazilian metals and mining corporation; I worked alongside a multidisciplinary team on a project, which included benchmarking visits and travelling to Vale's operation sites, identifying opportunities to improve productivity and providing tools for better visual management.